Daehwa Kim

291, Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, Republic of Korea daehwakim@kaist.ac.kr • +82 6860 8558 • https://daehwa.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is engineering for a fluid interface, exploring a seamless integration of a computer and human that makes new and pleasant experiences. My prior research lies in (a) novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs and (b) sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device. I published full papers at ACM CHI and UIST.

Sensing Techniques for Fluid Interfaces	novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs	sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device
	AtaTouch (Cond. Accepted CHl'21) + MagTouch (CHl'20)	OddEyeCam (UIST'20)OmniSense (Ongoing)

EDUCATION

KAIST, School of Computing

Mar 2019 – Feb 2021 (Expected)

- M.S. student at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
 - Adviser: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
 - Focus: Sensing Techniques
 - Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras"
 - o Thesis Committee: Geehyuk Lee (Chair), Juho Kim, Uichin Lee

UNIST, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 - Feb 2019

- B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering (Major)
 - B.S. in Electrical Engineering (Minor)
 - Thesis: "VRone: 3D Force Feedback System in VR Using a Commercial Drone"
 - · Entered with top honors.
- Summer session program, ual: (University of the Arts London), London, UK

Jul 2018

PUBLICATIONS

CONFERENCES

- [1] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return-Loss" To Appear in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. (full paper, To Appear)
- [2] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020. (full paper)
- [3] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020. (full paper)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

HCI Lab, KAIST

Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing

Mar 2018 – Jun 2018

Jan 2018 - Mar 2018

- Project: PCB design for a hand gesture sensing wristband.
- · Supervisors: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
- Focus: human-computer interaction, PCB design, physical prototyping

Hyper-connected Communication Research Laboratory, ETRI

- Research Intern, IoT Research Division
 - Project: Smart Home project Building IoT lighting system controlled by user's voice
 - Supervisors: Dr Jungsik Sung and Daeho Kim
 - Focus: IoT network system, Natural language processing

iHCI Lab (Intelligent Human Computer Interaction Lab), UNIST

- Undergraduate Research Student, Electrical and Computer Engineering
- Feb 2017 Nov 2017

- Project: Finger Joystick Interaction
- Supervisors: Prof. Sungahn Ko
- $\bullet\,$ Focus: human-computer interaction, visualization

Page 1 of 3

AWARDS &	Outstanding Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing	Feb 2021
SCHOLARSHIPS	■ Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interactio	n
	Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras"	
	4th Prize, NAVER x UNIST Undergraduate Poster Award	Dec 2017
	■ Topic: "VibCat: Vibration Categorization for Input and Interaction".	
	 Awarded by NAVER CEO. 	
	Received an award of 1,000,000 KRW.	
	Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016	Dec 2016
	 Dispatched to Uzbekistan to provide Android development lectures to university 	students.
	 Awarded by the Director of National Information Society Agency. 	
	 Received an award of Samsung Galaxy Tab 4 10.1. 	
	Academic Achievement Award, UNIST	
	2017 Fall Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.05/4.3	Jan 2018
	2017 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 3.98/4.3	Jul 2017
	2016 Fall Academic Achievement Award: GPA 3.90/4.3	Feb 2016
	2016 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.06/4.3	Aug 2016
	■ 2015 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.00/4.3	Jul 2015
	Uni-Star Scholarship, UNIST	Mar 2015 – Feb 2019
	■ Entered with top honors.	
	■ Tuition + academic support fee of 1,000,000 KRW were paid each semester.	T 2010
	Overseas Training Scholarship, UNIST	Jun 2018
	• Financial aid for the summer session program at University of the Arts London	
TEACHING	Teaching Assistant, AI Lab - Learning Commons II, UNIST	Sep 2018 – Dec 2018
EXPERIENCE	Head of Android Developement Team, HeXA, UNIST	Feb 2017 – Dec 2017
	Instructor , Tashkent University of Information Technologies (TUIT)	Jul 2016 – Sep 2016
	 Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016 	•
ACADEMIC	Reviewer	
SERVICE	• CHI '21 LBW	
	- CIII 21 LDW	
CAMPUS	D2 factory, NAVER	
ACTIVITIES	 Campus Partner 	Feb 2016 – Feb 2017
	 Hosted the 2nd Hackathon at UNIST, sponsored by NAVER and UNIST ECE 	
	HeXA (Hacker's eXciting Academy), UNIST	
	 A computer security & development research group 	
	■ Vice-President	Feb 2016 – Feb 2017
	 Head of Android development team 	Feb 2017 – Dec 2017
	Provided regular anndroid-development lectures for club members LINIST Madia Contact LINIST	
	UNIST Media Center, UNIST	M 2015 E-l- 2017
	Video Editor Depresentative veeds	Mar 2015 – Feb 2017
	 Representative work My Age 22 - Travel to Europe with a drone 	
	Web drama: The town where engineers live	
PDO IECTO	A. J. II.	Con 2010 Dec 2010
PROJECTS	Audio Hero	Sep 2019 – Dec 2019
	 Sound-based danger detection system using VGGish deep learning model Skiller Deep learning Signal processing 	
	 Skills: Deep learning, Signal processing VRone 	Sep 2018 – Dec 2018
	 3-dimensional force feedback in VR using a personal and commercial drone 	3cp 2010 – Dec 2010
	 Scaline is in the rectangle of the state of the rectangle of	
	System Light 2.0 @ ETRI	Jan 2018 – Mar 2018
	■ Smart Home project - Building IoT system for lights	
	 Skills: Computer network, Natural language processing 	
	VibCat	Oct 2017 – Dec 2017

■ Vibration Categorization for Input & Interaction

• Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

Finger joystick interaction

Feb 2017 - Nov 2017

- Interaction technique to support finger's directional input using capacitive image of a smartwatch's touchscreen
- Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

Poem a moment Mar 2017 – Jun 2017

- An android application that shows Yoon Dongju's poems on the wallpaper
- Available on Google Play store (download 1000+)
- Skills: Android programming

TUIT Android Lecture Jun 2016 – Sep 2016

- Android development lecture provided to TUIT university students
- Skills: Android programming, Object-oriented programming

Mr.Bill Jun 2016 – Jul 2016

- Algorithm and system to provide optimal Dutch pay way
- Available on Google Play store (download 500+)
- Skills: Android programming, Graph theory

[CV compiled on 2021-02-04 for Acme Corporation]